YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 1. General and History
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. GENERAL
  - Charter, Constitution, and By-laws
    - Constitution and By-laws
      - Committees
        - Constitution Commission, 1939, 1945-49 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
        - on Review of the National Board By-laws, 1940-49 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - By-laws Review, 1950-66 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
        - on Revision of the Constitution, 1956-64 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        - Constitution Review, 1964-66 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
        - Constitution and By-laws, 1972-98 (Box 6, Folder 3-8)
        - Reorganization Task Force, By-laws Subcommittee/Task Group, 2000-01 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1947-82, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - By Subject
          - Accreditation, Affiliation, Certification, and Disaffiliation, 1957-70, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
          - Authorized Groups/Organized Groups, 1951-81 (Box 6, Folder 13)
          - Board Member eligibility, 1967-82 (Box 7, Folder 1)
          - Constitutions and By-Laws of Community Associations, 1965-73 (Box 7, Folder 2)
          - Convention
            - General, 1963-78, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
            - Pluralistic delegations, 1973-75 (Box 7, Folder 4)
          - Membership of Associations and individuals, 1956-74 (Box 7, Folder 5)
          - Officers, 1957-81, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
          - Teens, membership eligibility, 1971-75 (Box 7, Folder 7)
          - Retirement Fund, 1975-79 (Box 7, Folder 8)
          - World Council Delegate Elections, 1973, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1932, 1934-46 (Box 7, Folder 10-14)
    - 1947-1984/85 (Box 8, Folder 1-10)
    - 1985/86-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
  - Committees, general
    - General and miscellaneous, 1900-64, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Charts, 1948-66 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Charters, 1958-59, 1965, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
    - Rosters, 1940-71, 1979, 1982-2001 (Box 10, Folder 7-13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Ethical Investments
        - Subcommittee of Finance Committee, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 14)
        - Committee
          - General, 1981-88 (Box 10, Folder 15-18)
          - Correspondence and reference material, 1973-84 (Box 11, Folder 1-6)
      - Middle East Task Force, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - National Educational Campaign Committee for the 1920 World Service Program, 1919-20 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Social and Economic Justice Task Force, circa 1973 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Special Committee on Plans for the Berlin Conference, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Study Group on Sexual Orientation, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - [New York] World's Fair Project, 1938-39 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Councils, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Department Charters, 1947, 1958-59 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - Organization charts, 1921-97 (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
  - Charts, miscellaneous, 1950-71, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Policies, miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Purpose/Mission
    - General, 1920-95 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - YWCA as a Single-Sex Organization
      - General, 1936-97, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 11-13)
      - Clippings, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 14-15)
  - Staff Rosters
    - "American Committee," 1891-1906 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - YWCA of the USA
      - 1906-25 (Box 12, Folder 17-21)
      - 1960-2000 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
  - Staff/Telephone/Office Directories
    - 1940-46, 1954-55, 1964-68, 1970-83 (Box 13, Folder 5-14)
    - 1984-92, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 1-9)
- SERIES II. REORGANIZATIONS/STRUCTURE OF THE YWCA
  - Survey of the Organization of the National Board (Fosdick and Jones)
    - Report, Sep 1921 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Report of the Reorganization Committee to the National Board, Mar 1921 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Committee on the Evaluation of the National Program for the Budget Reviewing Committee: minutes and report, 1929 (includes department and division reports) (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Report on a 1930 Survey and Proposals for the Future (Mark M. Jones), 1930
    - General, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Preliminary Report on 1930 Orientation Survey, Jan 1931 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Revised Report, Oct 1931 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Committee to Study Mr. Jones' Report
      - Minutes, Feb-May 1931 (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
      - Report, May 1931 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Report of the Transition Committee, Oct 1931 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Suggested Program of the Work of the National Board, November 1931 to December 1932 (Mark M. Jones): "Leaflet" 1, 1931-32, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - National Service Development Plan, 1934-39 by Mark M. Jones, 1932
    - Report and correspondence, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - Commission on Administrative Practices, 1938-39 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Fund-Raising Study and Report on the Foreign Division (John Price Jones Corporation): report, Jun 1946 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - "Study and Recommendations Concerning the Public Relations, Publicity and Fund-Raising of the National Board," submitted to the Committee on Financing the National Board (John Price Jones Corporation): report, Dec 1947 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Review of Studies and Major Actions on Structure of the National Board, 1921-53, prepared by Jane Dickey Britt, Jan 1954 (Box 16, Folder 2-4)
  - "Greenleigh Report" (Arthur Greenleigh, Greenleigh Associates, Management Consultants): report and summary, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - Committee on the Structure of the National Association/Board: minutes and reports, Jul 1961-Apr 1967 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - Organizational Renewal [Sub]Committee: correspondence, reports, and working papers, 1969-73 (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
  - Consultation on Organizational Relationships, Jan 1974 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Proposed Criteria for Evaluation of the National Board's Program and Present Way of Work, Jan 1975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Looking to the Future: A Plan for Study and Action (Human Services Design Laboratory, Case Western Reserve University)
    - Abstract and Study Design "Organizational Study: Needs and Directions for 1985", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Final Report, Oct 1977 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Final Report, annotated copy, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Response from YWCA departments, 1977-78 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1981-86, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 3-6)
  - National Executive Service Corps Study of YWCA Organization and Management Procedures, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Governance Task Force/Transition Team/Policy Committee
    - General, 1988-92 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - Register of Recommended Board Policies, 1988-89 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Resource material
      - General, 1986-88 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Carver Governance Design, Inc., circa 1987 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Project Redesign (KPMG Peat Marwick, Inc.)
    - General, 1992-93, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Final Report, Sep 1992 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Strategic Planning Initiative
    - General, 1994-2000, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Strategic Planning Committee
      - Rosters, 1995-98 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Meetings, 1996-97 (Box 18, Folder 4-6)
      - Affiliation Requirements Subcommittee, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Subcommittee on Environmental Scanning/Governance Task Force
        - General, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - Reports (Box 18, Folder 9)
        - Survey of National Organizations
          - Report (Box 18, Folder 10)
          - Interview notes (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Regional Forums, Round 1 (1994), Round 2 (1995), 1994-95 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Leadership Summits, Feb-Apr 1997
        - General (Box 18, Folder 13)
        - Resource packet (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
        - Reports
          - Feb (Box 18, Folder 16)
          - Mar-Apr (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
        - Staff (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Leadership Roundtables
        - 1999
          - General (Box 19, Folder 4)
          - Briefing packet (Box 19, Folder 5)
          - Evaluations (Box 19, Folder 6)
        - 2000
          - General (Box 19, Folder 7)
          - Briefing packet (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Reports
        - Miscellaneous, 1994-95, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 9)
        - "Report and Survey", 1997 (Box 19, Folder 10)
        - "YWCA [draft] Strategic Plan and Discussion Guide: Journey to the Future", [Jul 1995] (Box 19, Folder 11)
        - "YWCA Women 2000, Into the New Millenium: a Report to the Member Associations", [1996] (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Change Agent Team: minutes, notes, survey, and reports, 1997-98 (Box 19, Folder 13-14)
  - Strategic Investment Initiative/Strategic Initiative Plan (A.T. Kearney, consultants)
    - General, 1997-99 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
    - Recommendations and prioritization
      - Draft, 10 Feb 1988 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - 20 Feb 1998 (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
    - Appendix-detailed analysis of recommended investment initiatives, 20 Feb 1998 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    - Five Year Detailed Implementation Plan, 12 Jun 1998 (Box 20, Folder 9-11)
    - Presentation to the Board of Trustees, Jun 1998 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Dues Formula Presentation to Regional Councils, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Data Capture Inventory I, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Evaluation Report II (Data Capture Inventory II), Jun 2000 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Change Initiative/Steps to Absolute Change
    - General and History
      - Miscellaneous, 1998-2002, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
      - Newsletters, Mar 2000-Jun 2002 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Convention, 2000, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 7-9)
      - Regional Councils, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Steering Committee report, 19 Jan 1999 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - 'Open Space' meeting, Dallas, Oct 1999 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Issue Work Groups, Nov 1999-Aug 2000
      - General (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Governance, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Mission, Feb-Jun 2000, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 15-17)
      - Survival of Associations, Apr-May 2000 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Vision, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 'Accelerated Solutions Environment' meeting, Committee of 80, Dallas, Aug 2000 (Box 22)
      - General (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Transition Plan, 1 Sep 2000 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Transition Team/Transition Steering Committee (Sep 2000-Jul 2001)
      - 'Accelerated Solutions Environment' meeting, Chicago, Nov 2000 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Financial, 2000-01, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Memorandum of understanding re Executive responsibilities during Transition, 2000-01 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Project Management Office (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Proposed 'Operating System' and 'Operating Model': concept paper, convention report, and overheads, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 9-10)
      - Transition/Project Teams/Task Forces
        - General and charters (Box 22, Folder 11)
        - Advocacy Team (Box 22, Folder 12)
        - Branding Team (Box 22, Folder 13)
        - Hallmark Programs Team (Box 22, Folder 14)
        - Healthy Behaviors Team (Box 22, Folder 15)
        - Membership Team (Box 22, Folder 16)
        - Mission/Vision Team (Box 22, Folder 17)
        - Staff/Volunteer Development Team (Box 22, Folder 18)
        - Structure Team (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Transition Task Force/Reorganization Task Force (Aug 2001-02)
      - General, 2001-02, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 20-21)
      - Meetings, Aug 2001, Feb 2002 (Box 22, Folder 22-23)
      - Task Forces/Teams
        - Operations/Operating Review (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - Shared Vision (Box 23, Folder 2)
        - Student Outreach (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Work Groups
        - By-Laws (Box 23, Folder 4)
- SERIES III. MEMBERSHIP OF INDIVIDUALS
  - General and History
    - Thesis: "Membership in the Y.W.C.A.-History and Meaning" by Doris Ischinger, University of Southern California, School of Social Work, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Thesis: "Evidences of Membership Interpretation in the Y.W.C.A. as Shown in the 1952 Annual Reports" by Roberta (or Roberts) Chapman, Columbia University, School of Social Work, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Policies and Practices
    - General, 1, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    - Membership cards and forms, 1967-84, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Basis Commission/Committee on Education Concerning the Basis: minutes, reports, mailings, articles, 1914-19 (Box 24, Folder 6-8)
    - Basis/Committee on Membership Basis Education, 1920-36, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Corresponding Membership
      - History and general, 1920-31 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Commission on Individual Membership: reports and questionnaire, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Corresponding Membership Committee
        - Minutes, 1925-31 (Box 24, Folder 12-14)
        - Reports
          - General, 1923-31 (Box 24, Folder 15)
          - Secretary (Anna M. Clark), 1923-31 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Membership Commission, 1948-49 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Committee to Study National Membership Policy
      - General
        - 1952-Apr 1957 (Box 24, Folder 18-19)
        - May 1957-62 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
      - Minutes, 1956-58 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Study of Current Membership Policy, 1957-58 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
      - Study Project to Improve Membership Practices, 1959-60 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Membership Study, Oct-Dec 1971 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Ad-hoc Committee on Membership Policy, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Membership Task Force, 1991-93, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Publications (Box 25)
      - "Membership Policies and Practices in Community YWCAs", 1962, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - "Membership in Community YWCAs", 1974-80 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - "Working Papers to Help Associations Help Themselves in Improving Membership Practices", 1958 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - "Work Tool for the Organization and Maintenance of Membership and Program Participant Records in the YWCA", 1970 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Recruitment and Development
    - General, 1915-87, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - See What You've Got Into: Introducing the Y.W.C.A. to New Members by Margaret Hiller, 1937, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - New Dimensions of Membership: Program Packet, winter 1950 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Centennial Membership Development Committee, 1952-55 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - More Members: Guidelines for Membership Campaigns in Community YWCAs, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Membership Development Questionnaire, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Guidelines for the Membership Chair and the Membership Committee in a Community YWCA, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - "Why Double You?" Membership Drive, 1988-89
      - General, 1988-89 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Recruitment Handbook, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Membership in the YWCA: Research Reports, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- SERIES IV. ANNIVERSARIES
  - 1916: Jubilee, 50th Anniversary of founding of first YWCA in the U.S. (at that time credited to Boston, 1866), 1916
    - General (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - National Jubilee Committee: minutes and reports, 1915-16 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - 1932: "25th Anniversary of the Present National YWCA" (National Board of YWCAs of the USA, 1906), 1932 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - 1937: 25th Anniversary of national headquarters building at 600 Lexington Ave., New York, NY, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - 1944: 50th Anniversary of the founding of the organization called the World's Young Women's Christian Association, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - 1955: "World YWCA Centennial," 100th anniversary of founding of 2 organizations in England (1855) that later merged and took the name YWCA-first YWCA to be founded in the world, 1955
    - General, 1952-55, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Events, 1954-55 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Exhibition of paintings by Mary Bruce Sharon, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Membership Development Program, 1952-55 (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
    - Newsletter, Progress Report, 1954-55 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Program materials (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Publicity
      - General (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Publicity Committee (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Press, Radio and TV Guide (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Press releases, 1952-55 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Radio, TV and films (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Y-Teens (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - 1966: 60th Anniversary of U.S. national organization (1906) (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - 1983-84: 125th Anniversary of founding of Ladies Christian Association of New York (1858-by this time considered first YWCA in the U.S.) (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - 1993-94: 135th Anniversary of founding of Ladies Christian Association of New York (1858)
    - General (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Souvenir Program Journal (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Exhibit: "Women First for 135 Years, 1858-1993" (Box 28)
      - General, 1993-95, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
      - Text (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Advisory Committee (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Artifacts exhibit (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Brochure (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Budget (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Catalog (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Collages
        - General (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - #1, YWCA Residences in 50 States (Box 28, Folder 12)
        - #2, World War I Hostess Houses (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - #3, Selected National Board Properties (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
        - #4, Pioneering Health and Sex Issues (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - #5, Exercise, Sports and Nutrition (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - #6, Camps, Athletics and the Olympics (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - #7, YWCA Encourages Public Health (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - #8, The Industrial Worker and the YWCA (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - #9, New Job Skills Training (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - #10, Support Services for Working Mothers (Box 29, Folder 9)
        - #11, Girl Reserves and Y-Teens (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - #12, Rural Work (Box 29, Folder 11)
        - #13, Public Policy and Advocacy (Box 29, Folder 12)
        - #14, The Evolving Mission (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - #15, The Student Movement (Box 29, Folder 14)
        - #16, Preserving Cultural Identity (Box 29, Folder 15)
        - #17, Embracing Diversity (Box 29, Folder 16)
        - #18, The YWCA Moves on Freedom, Dignity and Racial Justice (Box 29, Folder 17)
        - #19, YWCA's Work in 86 Countries (Box 29, Folder 18)
        - #20, Emerging African Nations (Box 29, Folder 19)
        - #21, Relief in Time of Strife (Box 29, Folder 20)
        - #22, World YWCA (Box 29, Folder 21)
        - #23, WWI Serving Behind the Lines (Box 29, Folder 22)
        - #24, Training for Empowerment (Box 29, Folder 23)
        - #25, Leader Training Centers (Box 29, Folder 24)
        - #26, YWCA National Conventions: Public Policy and Membership, The Action Agenda (Box 29, Folder 25)
        - #27, Womans Press (Box 29, Folder 26)
        - #28, YWCA of the USA National Board Executives (Box 29, Folder 27)
        - 29, 135 Years of Leadership (Box 29, Folder 28)
        - #30, The White House and the YWCA (Box 29, Folder 29)
        - Aborted collage, World Service Council (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - Lenders to exhibit (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - Press kit (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Staff (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Travel
        - General, 1993-98 (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - Condition report (Box 30, Folder 4)
        - National Museum of Women in the Arts, Washington, DC, Oct-Nov 1993 (Box 30, Folder 5)
        - YWCA Leadership Development Center, Phoenix, Arizona, Feb-May 1994 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - YWCA 33rd National Convention, Westin-Bonaventure Hotel, Los Angeles, California, Jun-Aug 1994 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Dewitt Historical Society of Tomkins County, Ithaca, New York, Sep-Nov 1994 (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Baltimore Museum of Industry, Baltimore, Maryland, Nov 1994-Jan 1995 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - National Museum of Civil Rights, Memphis, Tennessee, Feb-Apr 1995 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        - Villa Terrace Decorative Arts Museum, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, May-Jul 1995 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        - Evansville Museum of Arts and Science, Evansville, Indiana, May-Jun 1996 (Box 30, Folder 12)
        - YWCA of the Central Carolinas, Charlotte, North Carolina, Aug-Oct 1995 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Postcard series (cancelled) (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Poster series (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - Who's Who in the YWCA of the U.S.A. special 135th Anniversary Commemorative Edition, Marquis Co., 1994 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - 1994: "World YWCA Centennial," 100th Anniversary of founding of the international organization called the World Young Women's Christian Association (1894), 1994
    - General (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Submissions for Convention book (Box 30, Folder 18)
- SERIES V. BIOGRAPHICAL FILES
  - A-Al (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, Alpha (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Julia F. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - An (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Constance (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Anderson, Eleanor Copenhaver (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Angle, Wesley M. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Ap-Az (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Ba - Barg (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Barn-Bay (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Baker, Gwendolyn Calvert (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Barnes, Lilace Reid
    - General (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Meditation given at 26th Convention, San Diego, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Juliet Blanchard, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Devotional materials, 1947-64 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Barrow, Nita
    - General (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - A Tribute to Dame Nita Barrow (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Bea - Bep (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Ber-Bez (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Beane, Ruth N. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Bertine, Eleanor (Box 32, Folder 3a)
  - Bi (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Bl (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Boa-Bor (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Bos-Boy (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Boardman, Dorothy (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Booth, Mary (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Bowles, Eva (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Boynton, Opal "Poppy" (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Bra-Bri (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Bremer, Edith Terry (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Brennecke, Margaret (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Brinkley, Dolores "Dee" (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Broa - Brom (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Broo-Bry (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Brown, Gladys L. (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Brown, Gladys S. (Mrs. Wright) (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Bryant, Erna (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Buck-Bur (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Bus-By (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Burkhead, Alice Clarkson (Mrs. F. M.) (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Burner, Oolooah (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Burton, Margaret (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Butler, Leontine (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Byram, Betsy (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Ca-Cam (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Can-Carp (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Carr-Carv (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Carner, Lucy Perkins
    - General (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Writings (Box 33, Folder 11a)
  - Carter, Eunice Hunton (Mrs. Lisle C.) (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Catto, Isabel (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Ce - Cha (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Che-Chz (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Chain, Claribel Ba Muang (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Chakko, Sara (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Chalmers, Frances K. (Mrs. Allan Knight) (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Chaplin, Virginia (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Christensen, Ethlyn (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Church, Margaret (Mrs. Fred J.) (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Cla (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Clary, Phoebe (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Claytor, Helen (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Cle - Con (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Coo (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Coit, Eleanor (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Conde, Bertha (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Coppock, Grace
    - General (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - G.L.C.: The Life of Grace Coppock by Helen Thoburn, 1923 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Grace Coppock, A Person for Today by Helen Thoburn, 1925 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Friendship Fund (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Writings (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Cor - Cra (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Cotton, Elizabeth Boies (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Coyle, Grace (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Cram, Mary Frances (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Cratty, Mabel
    - General (Box 34, Folder 14)